# Jamie Kwan

# **Experience Design** & Brand Strategy

363 Sorauren Ave #210 Toronto, ON, M6R 3C1 CANADA

+1 416.951.0760 jamiemkwan@gmail.com

#### Overview

# Multidisciplinary designer, strategist, and storyteller

with 5 years of experience working in the entertainment, architectural, and digital media industries.

I have a passion for creating branded stories in the real world. I champion the utilization of 'play' in design, creating inclusive, joyful, and impactful experiences that bridge the physical and digital worlds.

# **Experience**

# **Gensler** // Strategist (Brand & Experience Strategy)

JULY 2018 - PRESENT, TORONTO

As part of the Toronto Consulting team, I lead quantitative and qualitative research activities and interpret findings into actionable design concepts/strategies to meet client business objectives.

Development of design foresight and brand narratives, and creation of communication tools for clients to understand strategies for the design of spaces, services, and experiences.

#### **KEY PROJECTS**

- Toronto Int'l Film Festival (TIFF), Year-Round Attraction
- Cadillac Fairview, Holiday Tree (Experience Strategy)
- CIBC Square (Brand / EGD Content Strategy)
- Suncor Energy Centre, Workplace Pilot Project
- Suncor Control Room Guidelines
- Sandoz-Boucherville Workplace Strategy
- Ernst-Yeung 1MW (Digital Experience Design)

#### Studio Bud // Co-Founder

MARCH 2015 - PRESENT, TORONTO

Design of blue-sky ideation workshops with Gen Z, in partnership with client organizations, to uncover key market insights while creating the playful space for youth to engage with design thinking methodologies.

## **CLIENTS/PARTNERS**

- Cineplex Entertainment / Playdium
- Canon Canada
- SupaMaasai Foundation
- Heroes in Black
- Community Innovation Lab (Co-iLab)

#### \_

# **Experience**

(cont.)

# FORREC Ltd. // Designer (Creative Studio)

NOVEMBER 2015 - JULY 2018, TORONTO

Provided insight and direction for the integration of media-based themed entertainment attractions. Developed concepts for brand experiences for projects ranging from theme parks to museums to family entertainment centers.

Acted as Creative Director for several key projects in the Visitor Attractions sector, and developed winning concept packages for RFPs.

#### **KEY PROJECTS**

- Sanrio Hello Kitty CR Land
- La Mer Water Play Structure, Dubai
- Chudleigh's Farm (Brand Experience Strategy)
- B&O Railroad Museum, Vision 2020
- SkyCity Go-Cart Attraction, Hong Kong Int'l Airport
- Kaisa Dream Future Pavilion (Schematic Design)
- Mandai Planet Explorer (RFP Submission, Awarded)
- Panama Canal Tourism Plan
- Miraflores Visitor Centre, Panama City
- Xixi National Wetland Park, VR Attraction
- AS Roma Hall of Fame
- Recessed Tower, Riyadh (w. Bjarke Ingels Group)
- CJ Valley Masterplan (RFP Submission, Awarded)

#### Synaesthetic Media Lab // Graduate Research Assistant

JANUARY 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2015, TORONTO

Developed research prototypes for tangible and embodied user interfaces in the field of Human-Computer Interaction. Published academic papers and presented research findings at the Museums and the Web, DIS, and TEI Conferences, in 2016.

#### Junior Architect // SUSTAINABLE.TO Architecture + Building

AUGUST 2013 - JULY 2014, TORONTO

Assisted in the development of building permit and construction documentation for single-family residences, specifically with a focus on the integration of passive solar strategies and other green building features.

Led the design-build of the award-winning "Wild for Bees" campaign in collaboration with Burt's Bees, Fairmont Hotels & Resorts, and Pollinator Partnership Canada.

#### Special Projects Coordinator // IIDEX Canada

JANUARY 2013 - DECEMBER 2013, TORONTO

Research and coordination for the THINK: Material special feature exhibition, curated by international materials consultant, Jim Salazar. Development of photography and vendor outreach for both show floor exhibit and digital database. Performed administrative tasks related to sales and marketing.

# Speaking Engagements & Publications

Guest Lecturer / 4th Year Thesis Mentor (George Brown College)

Ideation Bootcamp Speaker (George Brown College, School of Design)

Panel, Immersive & Multisensory Museums (Museums & The Web, 2016)

#### // PUBLICATIONS

**May 2017.** "Creativity beyond the 9-5." Ryerson University Alumni Blog. [Co-Authored]

**Apr 2017.** "Empowering Cultural Preservation in China through Participatory Digitization." Journal of Archaeological Science: Reports. [Co-Authored]

**Dec 2016.** "Into the Millennial: Why Weirdos Will Change the World." OAA Perspectives Journal 24(4).

**Sep 2016.** "Form Follows Narrative: Pixel Experiences in a Collective Environment." OAA Perspectives Journal 24(3).

**Jun 2016.** "Sensing History: Contextualizing Artifacts with Sensory Interactions and Narrative Design." Proceedings of the 2016 ACM Conference on Designing Interactive Systems. [Co-Authored]

**Feb 2016.** "Towards a Framework for Tangible Narratives". Proceedings of the TEI '16: Tenth International Conference on Tangible, Embedded, and Embodied Interaction. [Co-Authored]

**Feb 2016.** "Grasping Cultural Context through Multisensory Interactions." Proceedings of the TEI '16: Tenth International Conference on Tangible, Embedded, and Embodied Interaction. [Co-Authored]

**Jan 2016.** "Sensing context: Reflexive design principles for intersensory museum interactions." Museums and the Web. [Co-Authored]

# **Passion Projects**

**Design on the Mind (Design & Lifestyle Blog)** 

Data Doodles (Hand-Sketched Data Visualization Project)

Narrative + Drive (Transmedia Storytelling Group)

Curiosity in Focus (Co-Producer, Podcast)

## **Education**

## Ryerson University // Masters in Digital Media (MDM)

2014 - 2015, TORONTO

Ontario Graduate Fellowship

Ryerson University // Bachelor of Architectural Science (BArchSc)

2009 - 2013, TORONTO

Undergraduate Research Opportunity (URO) Grant Toronto Society of Architects Award Alexander Budrevics Associates Award